





Punitha A Punitha A Featured 12+ years of experience in Payment domain handling payment application|Proficient in Core Java, J2EE, Spring 4.3.x, Web Services, JavaScript, Ajax, JSP, Servlets, HTML, JDBC, Oracle, Maven and ANT|Experienced with Waterfall and Agile methodology Current Designation: Project Lead - Acquiring Total Experience: 12 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Company: Financial Software and Systems Private Notice Period: 2 Months Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers] Current Location: Chennai Pref. Location: Chennai Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead Industry: IT-Software/Software Services Marital Status: Married Key Skills: Core Java, J2EE, Spring M/C, Web Services, JavaScript, Ajax, JSP, Servlets, HTML, JDBC, Oracle, Maven and ANT Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Jump to Section Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

Summary

Last Active: 22-Jan-21

12+ years of experience in Payment domain handling payment application.

Extensive functional knowledge on EMV Co 3D Secure 3D Secure 2.1.0, 1.0.2, Global Schemes VISA, MASTER, AMEX, and Switch System Base24(ISO 8583).

Skillful at developing multiple interfaces by reuse of modules using M/C architecture.

Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Experienced in creating transaction modules using Web Services like SOAP and Restful.

Working knowledge on XML Technologies JAXP DOM and SAX parsers.

Experienced in writing Maven scripts to build and deploy Java applications

Knowledge on generating CSR and importing p12 certificate using portcle tool.

Efficient at general problem solving and strong in providing object-oriented solutions.

Experienced with Waterfall and Agile methodology in different phases of Software Development Life Cycle.

Strong analytical skills with ability to quickly understand client's business needs.

Use of Log4J for effective logging. Used other tools like Putty, WinSCP, etc.

Work Experience

Financial Software and Systems Private Ltd. as Project Lead - Acquiring Jun 2010 to Till Date

Actively involved in creating Project Plan, Project Schedule, Estimates and Managing resource allocation.

Internal and external client interactions. Contributed in CMMIevel5 certifications

Motivate and empower the team to solve the business problems.

Providing overall leadership to the entire team including managing deliverables of other functional team leaders in an effective manner.

Following the Project Life Cycle methodology like Agile and Waterfall defined under the process framework ensured that customer deadlines were met within project budgets

Responsible for working closely with business analysts to understand the requirements and translating requirements into system work

Manage new feature developments and defect using agile process.

Direct and track team velocity and sprint/release progress

Conduct code reviews to maintain quality of code.

Coordinate and manage code releases and share APIs.

Collaborate with cross functional teams, engineers, product managers and support specialists on product issues. Proper guidance provided to team members to handle all the issues and release the product with customer satisfaction and zero defects

Thinsy Corporation as Software Engineer Feb 2008 to May 2010

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

prayback reatures which can be used as virtual classroom or virtual conference room. In the enterprise sector, conference with desktop can be recorded and played back using the player. In the educational arena, classes could be recorded with desktop & played back using the player. Participants can have their audio/video conference with the moderator desktop being shared.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Anna University in 2006

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Certificate Of Completion - Appsec Curriculum

Certificate Of Completion - COD 222 - PCI DSS 3.2 Best Practices for Developers

Certificate Of Completion - Fundamentals of Threat Modeling

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
CORE JAVA	1.8	2021	10 Year(s)
SPRING M/C	4.3.x	2021	8 Year(s)
WEB SERVICES		2021	6 Year(s)
Oracle JDBC		2021	8 Year(s)
JavaScript		2021	6 Year(s)
JSP		2021	6 Year(s)
AJAX		2021	5 Year(s)
Hibernate		2016	2 Year(s)
Waterfall, Agile, Iterative, Windows			
Apache Tomcat, JBoss, WebLogic			
Confluence, JIRA, Jenkins, MySQL			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Tamil	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: Product Features

Client: Middle east region, HDFC, SBI and ICICI

Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Chennai Role: Project Leader

Duration: Jun 2010 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 8

Skill Used: Core Java, Spring Mc, J2Ee, Web Services, oracle jdbc,javascript,ajax, JSP Servlets

Role Description: Actively involved in creating Project Plan, Project Schedule, Estimates and Managing resource allocation.

? Internal and external client interactions

Responsible for working closely with business analysts to understand the requirements and translati

Project Details: Payment Gateway System Powering online transactions to support customer payments completing authentication & authorization.

- ? 3D Secure 1.0 and 2.0 Integration Payment Gateway provides banks and merchant with secure e-commerce transaction through 3D secure.
- ? SDK development for 1.0 and 2.0 App Based platform provides seamless experience to user.
- ? Rupay Integration Process Seamless and Redirection flow, EMI and SI transactions (This Integration will allow the consumers to perform a safe and fast checkout process)
- ? Rule-based risk and fraud control mechanism Built-in engine in the Payment Gateway system to minimize the fraud exposure.
- ? Pay Now feature implementation Invoice payments
- ? Shopping Carts WooCommerce, magneto and shopify
- Wallet Integrations Samsung pay, google pay and apple pay integration (Mobile payment and digital wallet service which enables seamless online checkout experiences for payers).
- ? Dynamic ISO Mapper
- ? Open source jar scan using OWSAP depen

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

Job Type: Permanent

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.